Hey there, welcome to the Grow Your Life
podcast. My name is Jeremiah Rowski. I
want to talk about a way that can help
you save a lot of time in your business,
which is outsourcing. And I never
understood outsourcing for the longest
time. I wish I had this video right here
when I started in my business. Number
one thing is it's not as complicated as
we make it. Number two, you really need
to learn how to a recognize talent and b
how to manage people well. And so those
are the two skills that I want to help
you with by the end of this training is
to walk you through to be able to do
that. Number one, one of my favorite
resources for hiring, there's a couple
of them that are out there. I'm going to
show you just on the websites, online
jobs.ph. Still one of my favorites.
Hiring Filipino workers in the
Philippines. uh people that can help you
with your copywriting, uh your ads, your
graphics, all those types of things. So,
really incredible community. Love it. Uh
a couple of others that are honorable
mentions.
Upwork.com. You can hire some people on
upwork.com that are freelancers that can
help you. Uh as well as
Fiverr. Fiverr.com
uh does like oneoff jobs for that. Now,
to figure out what your job is and how
to make a listing, I'm g tell you you
want to use AI for this. And so, you
could literally put um I want to hire a
video editor to make Instagram reels and
edit them. Uh I'm posting on online
jobs. PH and Upwork. Write me a detailed
listing to
attract top
talent at affordable price. Okay. And so
what it's going to do, the AI is
literally going to go to work to write
for us the job listing uh for you. Now
again, this is taking in mind a lot of
like the different stuff that we have
done with our clients, things like that.
It's pulling all that into there. But
yes, right here literally is showing you
exactly how to make a job listing. So if
you're like, I don't know what to post.
I don't know what to share. AI will help
you with that. Okay. Um, now to figure
out who are the best people to hire,
here's what I do is whenever I make a
listing on these sites, I'm going to get
oftentimes hundreds of applications. I
look for one thing and one thing
only. Price. No, that's not it. Uh,
well, I do look for what is the price,
what are they charging per hour um for
that.
And I do I'm not going to hire somebody
who is charging me three times as much
per hour as what my budget is. So, I'm
going to eliminate off of the list of
say 500 people that might have applied
for a job, anybody who is above my
price. And that might oftentimes
eliminate about 50 to 70% of the people
who applied. Um, beyond that, then what
I look for is the ones who are within
the price range I'm looking for. Uh, not
the cheapest price, but a little bit
above the lowest cost is usually what I
look for. I then look for what are their
portfolios and responses. Now, the
cheapest price people often are terrible
at doing this. Sending the stuff you
actually asked for. So, if you made this
listing like with chat GBT, it's asking
for different examples and showing what
you want to see from them and how they
can share this, how to apply, what to
what to share with you, what links.
Chances are, most people who are
applying are not going to follow your
directions. And listen, if they can't
follow the directions in the
application, they're not going to follow
your directions when you're hiring them.
So, just eliminate anybody who did
literally didn't do what you asked for.
Like it's as simple as that. Like sorry
that eliminates about 80 to 90% of the
remaining applicants. Now the higher
cost applicants are usually more likely
to actually do what you said. But the
lower cost ones oftent times maybe
they're trying to build their portfolio.
They're trying to start out. They still
have great quality. And so then what
I'll do is I'll look at the ones who
actually did what they said they're
going to
do. They actually followed through.
um which ones do I like what they have
their their their
uh style and I really want it to match
whatever style that I see in the
examples that they're giving me is going
to be the style that I'm going to get
from them when I hire them because
they're not going to just change their
style uh for me. I'm not going to expect
anybody that I'm hiring to to do
something different in the style that I
want. And that's a key that I want you
to understand when you're hiring people
is that it's really hard to
um teach somebody new methods when
you're just starting out with them. Now,
over time, you can train people with new
skill sets and things like that, and I
have learned how to do that. But when
you're hiring the person at first, you
want them to as closely match what
you're trying to accomplish as possible
in the examples they sent you, because
that's exactly what you're going to get
out of them. Okay? So, and then what
you'll find is literally out of 500
people, you might literally only have
two people that fit all those
qualifications. And those are two people
that now you can do a test run with. And
I'll tell you, by doing this, we've
weeded out to the best possible
candidates in price, in being able to
follow directions, um, and actually
producing a style that is something
similar to what we're wanting. And this
is
not I've never gone wrong with this
process with doing this when hiring
people uh on these sites when
outsourcing. And so then I'll send them
like a test run and things like that
that I want. Don't pay them a big lump
sum up front. Pay them for upfront for
maybe like a week of
work. You could also say, "Hey, I only
want to pay you for 10 hours this week."
That's another great thing to do. Um I
like to start with 10 hours usually with
these people. So, I'm going to say
you're going to do 10 hours this week
and I'm going to pay you for that. So,
if they're if they're six bucks an hour,
by the way, that's all they charge. All
you got to pay is like 60 bucks and you
got 10 hours of work with somebody and
they might be able to crank out like
five 10 videos for you during that time.
It's amazing. Let's say you're hiring
somebody for Instagram reels or
something like that. Okay. Now, comes to
management. Oftent times when we hire
people, they get complacent and they get
comfortable. And when people get
comfortable, they get sloppy and they
make mistakes. Now, I am a huge
proponent proponent of not micromanaging
people. I am a huge proponent of
teaching people how to be
self-governing. Um, however, it's also
my company and I need to look at, okay,
are they actually doing their job? Are
they actually doing what they're
supposed to do? And if they don't, I'm
going to let them know as quickly as
possible. Had this happen recently. had
to let one of our staff members know,
hey, you didn't do your job. What
happened? This is not acceptable. It's
not going to work. No emotion. Don't be
emotional. Don't don't yell. Don't get
emotional, but be direct and tell them
what's not working, what needs to
change, what needs to improve. And then
what I like to do is I always offer
their help. I encourage them. I tell
them they're doing a great job, that I
believe in them, that they that they're
I know that they're going to be able to
to get this right, and that I'm here for
them if they need help, if they need to
some guidance, some direction, if they
want to talk through anything. And what
I found is by doing that, I can usually
often get somebody back on track. If
somebody gets back on track um right
away, that's great. If they're not, and
I still get
repeated issues going on, had this
happen as well with another staff
member. I had to let them go. Had to
fire them. Had to let them They were
making some very silly mistakes that
were costing me a lot of money. And
quite frankly, probably should have let
them go sooner than I did. But it was a
tough lesson to learn. And so,
understand that, you know, you want to
um you want to hire fast and fire fast.
And that that's that's something that
like I I would say a lot of people are
are they're hesitant to fire people.
They want to hire quickly. I I when I
say hire fast, I don't want to take a
lot of time from the time they put in an
application to hiring. I want to be able
to just weed out all the ones that
aren't worth it. I have a system for
that and then I'm going to hire somebody
pretty quickly. But then if they're not
working out, I'm going to fire them and
I'm not going to continue working with
them. I have standards that I expect and
I and how I expect things to be. And so,
listen, if you follow this and you can
learn how to guide and direct people
really well, you can really help
people do their job better. And one of
the best ways that you can help people
do their job better is by recording your
screen, such as recording it through
here or through a Zoom meeting. You can
send recordings. Let's say there's a
task that you want to walk them through
to do they're not quite sure how to do.
I always record my screen, show them
exactly what it is that I want them to
take, and then send that to them. Now,
in my wealthy coach academy program, we
actually have a whole course all about
outsourcing and team building. Um, I
give a list of vetted service providers
that you could hire uh that we've worked
with. Um, but the number one thing to to
realize is that yeah, if you're going to
grow your business, if you're going to
scale, it's got to happen with more than
just you. And you don't need to have big
salaries. You can hire people part-time,
10, 20 hours a week, part-time, very
part-time overseas like this, and be
able to get great results. I, you know,
I have people that work with me that are
$3 an hour. I got people that work with
me that are $7 an hour. I got people
that work with me that are $27 an hour.
And and and uh they're in all different
parts of the country, you know,
including we have some people that are
here in the United States. And so with
that, we figure out, okay, what's
working out best? All the people that
have worked with me, they've been with
me for a long time and they love it and
they tell me they really enjoy it
because again, I let them be
self-governing. I let them manage their
own time. I let them choose and decide
when they want to work. I'm not super
controlling. Um, but I'm direct and I
tell them what I want and they and they
accomplish it when I tell them what I
want. And then I let them run with it
and I don't micromanage it from there.
if things aren't working out, okay, I'm
going to help course correct, but not
getting into that micromanagement type
of hole. Okay, so I hope that this helps
you if you're somebody that wants to
build your business, break past burnout,
and be able to scale your coaching
business fast, being able to hire people
is one of the fastest and best ways to
do that. All right, if you want to jump
into my wealthy coach academy program,
I'd love to see you in there, help you
become one of the wealthiest coaches on
the planet. It's what we help people do
every single week. And so go check it
out. Next time we open the doors, you
can jump in. You can also check out more
about it by going to
jeremicowsky.com00k. 1000 the letter K.
And that's going to actually show you
how to get started with us and maybe
skip the line as well. All right. So
grow your life everybody. We'll talk
soon. I'll see you in the next lesson.
[Music]